Guide to the Cornell University College of Architecture, Art, and Planning Records, 1905-2004
College of Architecture, Art, and Planning, Cornell University, Records, 1905-2004
- Series I. Administrative/departmental files
  - Faculty Meetings Minutes and Memoranda, 1960-10-1965-06 (Box 83)
  - Faculty Meetings Minutes and Memoranda, 1965-10-1971-06 (Box 83)
  - Faculty Meetings Minutes and Memoranda, 1971-09-1980-05 (Box 83)
  - National Planning Board Final Report, 1933-1934 (Box 14)
    Note: The National Planning Board, the National Resources Board and the Natioanl Resources Committee are the same organization
  - National Resources Board Report, Dec. 1, 1934 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Regional Planning Part I Pacific Northwest, May 1936 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Regional Planning Part II St. Louis Region, June 1936 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Regional Planning Part III New England, July 1936 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Deficiencies in Basic Hydrologic Data, Sept. 1936 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Our Cities, June 1936 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Drainage Basin Problems and Programs, Feb. 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Future of State Planning, Mar. 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Problems of a Changing Population, May 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Consumer Incomes in the U.S., Aug. 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Research, A National Resource, Dec. 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Progress Report, Dec. 1938 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Progress Report, June 1939 (Box 14)
  - National Resources Committee - Consumer Expenditures in the U.S., 1939 (Box 14)
  - Legal Problems in Housing Field, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Maryland State Planning Committee Part IV, Nov. 1937 (Box 14)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority - Recreational Development of Central Highlands Region, July 1938 (Box 14)
  - Terra Cotta of the Italian Renaissance - Natural Terra Cotta Society, New York, 1925 (Box 14)
  - College of Architecture, Art, and Planning/Cornell University (photocopy), 1978 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - College Seals and Medals, 1979-1985 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - College Annual Reports, 1991-1994 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Locey, Jean, 1993-1999 (Box 80, Folder 12)
- Series II. Olmstead Brothers, Brookline, Mass, (1 envelope)
  Contains 20 Planting Plans for Residences and a smaller envelope of photos of Landscaped Areas
  - J.E. Aldred, Glen Cove, Long Island, NY - File No. 5578, (Revised), Feb. 14, 1917 (Box 14)
  - J.E. Aldred, "Ormston," Glen Cove, Long Island, NY - to accompany Plan No. 618, Nov. 18, 1922 (Box 14)
  - J.E. Aldred, Glen Cove, Long Island, NY - File No. 5578-D, Mar. 23, 1923 (Box 14)
  - H.P. Bingham, Cleveland, OH - File No. 6405, July 15, 1920 (Box 14)
  - Edward Bok, Mountain Lake, Fl - File No. 6936, Sept. 20, 1923 (Box 14)
  - James A. Burden, Syosset, Long Island, NY - File No. 7040, Feb. 13, 1923 (Box 14)
  - George A. Cluett, Williamstown, MA - File No. 6907, Sept. 4, 1923 (Box 14)
  - Dr. Walter James, Cold Spring Harbor, NY - File No. 6904, Mar. 14, 1921 (Box 14)
  - Walter Jennings, Cold Spring Habor, NY - File No. 6904, Mar. 14, 1941 (Box 14)
  - Duncan McDuffie, Esq., Berkeley CA, Jan. 12, 1915 (Box 14)
  - E. Richard Meinig, Wyomissing, PA - File No. 6864, Sept. 5, 1922 (Box 14)
  - S.Z. Mitchell, Brookville, Long Isalnd, NY - File No. 6939, Aug. 16, 1923 (Box 14)
  - C.E. Steffey, Dayton, OH - File No. 6897, General Planting Plan No. 5, Mar. 10, 1921 (Box 14)
  - Loren D. Towle, Newton, MA - File No. 6251-0, Oct. 21, 1920 (Box 14)
  - Loren D. Towle, Newton, MA - Plan 6251-152, Mar. 22, 1921 (Box 14)
  - Jackson Heights Gardens, Apartments, Elmhurst, Long Island, NY - File No. 7142, Oct. 31, 1922 (Box 14)
  - F.M. Kirby Park, Wilkes-Barre, PA - File No. 6935, Sept. 21, 1923 (Box 14)
  - Memorial Park, Jacksonville, FL - File No. 5151, (Revised), Jan 18, 1923 (Box 14)
  - "Photographs for Professor Ralph Curtis, College of Agriculture, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y." (small enevelope) (Box 14)
    Most of them accompany the above plans for Aldred, Bok, Bingham, James, Jennings, Meinig, Mitchell, and L.D. Towle; also for the Taft School and for De Forest
- 3 Mimeos, School of Argiculture (1 folder), 1919-1920, Nov. 1922 (Box 14)
  1) Landscape Art #17 Outline, n.d. 2) Alphabetical Planning List, 3) Classified Planting List
- A-Ad, 1943-1955 (Box 15)
- Ai-As, 1943-1955 (Box 16)
- B-E, 1943-1955 (Box 17)
- F-M, 1943-1955 (Box 18)
- N-Po, 1943-1955 (Box 19)
- Pr-S, 1943-1955 (Box 20)
- Si-W, 1943-1955 (Box 21)
- A-V, 1953-1954 (Box 22)
- A-V, 1954-1955 (Box 23)
- A-P, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
- R-V, 1955-1956 (Box 25)
- A-D, 1940-1957 (Box 25)
- E-U, 1955-1958 (Box 26)
- Ad, 1957-1958 (Box 26)
- A.I.A. - N, 1957-1958 (Box 27)
- O-Y, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
- A-E, 1958-1959 (Box 28)
- F-W, 1958-1959 (Box 29)
- A-M, 1959-1960 (Box 30)
- N-V, 1959-1960 (Box 31)
- A-Ag, 1960-1967 (Box 31)
- A.I.A. - App, 1960-1967 (Box 32)
- App-Aw, 1960-1967 (Box 33)
- B-Cor, 1960-1967 (Box 34)
- Corr-E, 1960-1967 (Box 35)
- F-G, 1960-1967 (Box 36)
- H - Misc. Corres., 1960-1967 (Box 37)
- Misc. Rep. - New York City, 1960-1967 (Box 38)
- New York Field - Reg. Office, 1960-1967 (Box 39)
- Reg. Office - S, 1960-1967 (Box 40)
- T - Vice, 1960-1967 (Box 41)
- Visiting - Y, 1960-1967 (Box 42)
- A-As, 1967-1968 (Box 42)
- B-M, 1967-1968 (Box 43)
- N-T, 1967-1968 (Box 44)
- U-Y, 1967-1968 (Box 45)
- A-B, 1968-1969 (Box 45)
- C-M, 1968-1969 (Box 46)
- N-Z, 1968-1969 (Box 47)
- A-Con, 1966-1970 (Box 48)
- Cor-M, 1966-1969 (Box 49)
- N-Univ, 1966-1969 (Box 50)
- Ur-Y, 1966-1969 (Box 51)
- A-Coo, 1971-1973 (Box 51)
- Cor-M, 1971-1973 (Box 52)
- N-Z, 1971-1973 (Box 53)
- Dean Burnham Kelly's files - Correspondence A-H, 1970-1971 (Box 55)
- Dean Kelly's files - Correspondence N-P, 1970-1971 (Box 56)
- Dean Kelly (some Parsons'?) files - Correspondence C, S-Y, 1970-1971 (Box 57)
- Deans Kelly and Parsons files - Correspondence C-L, 1970-1972 (Box 58)
- Dean Kermit C. Parsons' files - Correspondence A-C, 1971-1972 (Box 59)
- Dean Parsons' files - Correspondence M-Z, 1971-1972 (Box 60)
- Dean Parsons' files - Admissions correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 61)
- Dean Parsons' files - Correspondence A-C, 1973-1974 (Box 62)
- Dean Parsons' files - Correspondence C (cont.)-P, 1973-1974 (Box 63)
- Dean Parsons' files - Correspondence P (cont.)-W, 1973-1974 (Box 64)
- Dean Kelly's files - Correspondence, inc. files on alumni, budget, memos, New York City Program, payroll and personal, ca., 1964-1971 (Box 65)
- Dean Parsons' papers - Notes and drafts on "The University in Urban Change," ca., 1971-1973 (Box 66)
- Dean Thomas W. Mackesey's papers - Correspondence and plans for College of Architecture maintenance, ca., 1952-1963 (Box 67)
- Archives - memo, letter, postcard, 1945,1946,1954 (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Art Museum - Proposal of Establishment At Cornell University from 1940, 1940-1951 (Box 68, Folder 2)
- Arts Report - report, memos, proposals, photocopied agenda, 1964-1966 (Box 68, Folder 3)
- Barnette Report, - reports, ms. listing, statement, typescript letters, May 1956 (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Chapman Collection - memo, report, typescript letters, 1942,1947 (Box 68, Folder 5)
- Roger P. Clark Paintings - lists of paintings, typescript letters, 1940,1947,1952 (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Committee on the Arts - Minutes, 1964,1965 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  Schedule of meetings, report, agenda, program, memos, photocopied program, correspondence, photocopied minutes
- Committee on Arts, Kelly Documents, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  Pamphlets, photocopy of a review article, correspondence, report, photocopy of essay, summary, photocopied letter, photocopied bulletin
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1939-1941,1950 (Box 68, Folder 9)
- Mrs. E. Day, National Sculpture Society - typescript letters, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 10)
- Directors Reports - reports, program, correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 68, Folder 11)
- Division of Creative Arts (History of Museum) - correspondence, memo, ms. reports, notes, petition, 1952-1953 (Box 68, Folder 12)
- Documents, Local, 1965-1966 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  Newspaper articles, photocopied questionnaires, photocopied letters, memo, reports, correspondence, photocopied memos, photocopied review essays, photocopied report, photocopied act S.1483, minutes, multicopied speech, summary
- Dondero - photocopied review articles, speech, statement, 1950,1952 (Box 68, Folder 14)
- Eilshemius (Rabin and Krueger) - catalogue (annotated), memo, ms. letter, typescript letter, 1939-1940 (Box 68, Folder 15)
- Programs of Exhibitions - catalogues, 1950-1953 (Box 68, Folder 16)
- Mrs. Livingston Farrand - ms. letters, correspondence, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 17)
- Mrs. Livingston Farrand - ms. letter, correspondence, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 17)
- Mrs. Edith M. Fox - correspondence, course catalogues, 1954-1955 (Box 68, Folder 18)
- C.L. Goeller Articles - photograph, articles, ms. letter, typescript letters, 1941,1943 (Box 68, Folder 19)
- Graduate School - Division of Arch. and Fine Arts - memo, 1946 (Box 68, Folder 20)
- Historical Art Department - minutes of meeting, correspondence, 1940 (Box 68, Folder 21)
- Humanities Council - letters, memos, ms. note, resumes, 1958 (Box 68, Folder 22)
- Ikle, Mr. Charles - ms. notes, correspondence, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 23)
- Industrial Design, Slide Material - photographs, correspondence, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 24)
- Kane, Robert - correspondence, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 25)
- Dr. C.W. De Kiewiet - ms. letters, memo, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 26)
- Laufman, Sidney (Third Woodstock Art Conference) - posters, memo, correspondence, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 27)
- Lougee, Arthur T. - correspondence, 1951-1958 (Box 68, Folder 28)
- Museum - correspondence, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 29)
- Music Committee, 1944-1948 (Box 68, Folder 30)
  Catalogue, minutes, programs, order blank, listings, memos, financial report, ms. letter
- National Art Week Report - 1940, John A. Hartell, 1940-1941 (Box 68, Folder 31)
  Correspondence, financial statement, report
- Newhouse Gallery to B.E. Truman - correspondence, photographs, 1944 (Box 68, Folder 32)
- New York State Art Program Committee - pamphlets, reports, memo, correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 68, Folder 33)
- Report on Schools of Architecture, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 34)
- Rogalsky, George F., Vice-President Business, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 35)
- Shur, William - correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 68, Folder 36)
- U.N.E.S.C.O. - report, pamphlets, correspondence, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 37)
- University Publisher - correspondence, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 38)
- Warner, Industrial Design - report, bulletin, memos, 1941-1944 (Box 68, Folder 39)
- White Museum Minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 68, Folder 40)
- White Museum, Advisory Committee Reports Correspondence Opponents Charge, 1952-1956 (Box 68, Folder 41)
  ms. notes, catalogues, minutes, by-laws, correspondence
- Current - White Museum, 1953-1957 (Box 68, Folder 42)
  ms. notes, ms. report, correspondence, minutes, memo
- White Museum - Advisory Committee, 1952-1957 (Box 68, Folder 43)
  List of paintings, ms. notes, memo, correspondence, program
- White Museum of Art - correspondence, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 44)
- Willard Straight Art - ms. notes, memos, photocopied letters, photocopied resumes, correspondence, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 45)
- Willard Straight Art Selection - ms. postcard, photocopied letter, memo, listing, ms. notes (Box 68, Folder 46)
- "Festival of Contemporary Arts." Cornell University, Ithaca, New York., April 28-May 14, 1949 (Box 68)
- R.E. Treman, "The Scriber Picture Publications." Ithaca, Triangle Book Shop, 1907 (Box 68)
- "Second Festival of Contemporary American Arts," Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1946 (Box 68)
- "Fifteen Poets," Fourteenth Festival of Contemporary Arts, Cornell University, 1960 (Box 68)
- "Five Poets," Fourteenth Festival of Contemporary Arts, Cornell University, 1960 (Box 68)
- Various undescribed material. (Box 70-77)
- Dragon Day Scrapbook (Box 77)
- Plans and drawings (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Plans and drawings (Mapcase-folder 2)
- Series III. Advisory Council and Trustees
  - Advisory Council files, 1980-2003 (Box 78, Folder 1-3)
  - Advisory Council Reports, 1983-2004 (Box 78, Folder 4-5)
  - Trustee Council Weekends, 1982-2001 (Box 78, Folder 6-10)
- Series IV. Events, Projects and Programs
  - Alumni in Residence Program, 1984-1995 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1984-1986 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Art Auction, 1994-1995 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Buzz Spector - Vero Beach, 2004 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Colloquia, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Cornell in Rome Program Dedication, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Cornell in Rome Program, 1995-2002 (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Journal of Architecture, 1981-1989 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Cornell Women Artists - exhibit, 2000 (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Community Service Project, 1981-1983 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Continuing Education - Summer, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Friends of Cornell Architecture, 1992-1993 (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Geographic Information Systems and Computer Aided Design Project, 1982-1996 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Historic Preservation Program, 1980-2000 (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - Landscape Architecture, 1973, 1979 (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - MacDougal Slide Project, 1986-1989 (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - 125th Anniversary College Celebration, 1996 (Box 78, Folder 27-30)
  - President's Council of Cornell Women, 1997-2002 (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - Reunions, 1990-2003 (Box 78, Folder 32-38)
  - South Asian Studies Project, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Gargoyle Society, 1963-1968 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Women Architect's Exhibition, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Urban Scholars Program in New York City, 2002 (Box 79, Folder 4)
- Series V. Conferences/Seminars
  - MacKesey Seminars, 1981-1989 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Mayors' Symposium - "Economy, Society and Environment: Are World Cities Sustainable?", 1991 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - 50th Anniversary Conference - City and Regional Planning, 1984-1985 (Box 79, Folder 7)
- Series VI. Correspondence, Articles and Memos
  - Donor Correspondence, 1980-1997 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, press releases, correspondence, flyers, posters, and memos on the history of the college and various other topics, 1967-2004 (Box 79, Folder 9-13)
  - Articles on the Dept. of Art, 1984-2002 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Articles on City and Regional Planning Dept., 2001-2005 (Box 79, Folder 15)
- Series VII. Facilities
  - A.D. White Photo Collection - Knight Visual Resources Facility, 1979-2001 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Imaging Center, 1992-1994 (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Media System Proposal, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Video Disk Project, 1983-1992 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Miller-Heller House, 1945-2002 (Box 79, Folder 20)
- Series VIII. Memorial Funds
  - Michael Baum Memorial, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Hartell Fund, 1980-1996 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Hartell Gallery Opening, 1982-1983 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Preston H. Thomas Memorial Fund, 1978-1993 (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - Preston H. Thomas Memorial Fund, 1990s-2002 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - Morrie Wells Memorial Fund, 1980s (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - Memorial Medal Fund, 1980-1981 (Box 79, Folder 27)
- Series IX. Photographs and Artwork
  - Photographs and artwork, 1980s (Box 79, Folder 28)
  - Invitations/announcements, 1980s (Box 79, Folder 29)
  - Photographs, sketches, contact sheets, 1980s-1990s (Box 79, Folder 30)
  - Photos of northeast alumni; Whitney reception; landscape architecture work at Heller House, 1982-1985 (Box 79, Folder 31)
  - Photos of receptions and MacKesey Assembly, 1970s-1980s (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Photos of faculty and faculty work, 1980s-1990s (Box 80, Folder 2-4)
  - Photos, slides of art students and studios, 1980s-1990s (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
  - Photos, negatives of various college activities, 1940s-1970s (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Photos of campus scenes, 1970s-1990s (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Photos of Dragon Day and Freshman Water Drop, 1980s (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Photos, Articles of Dragon Day, 1984-2003 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Photography Class I at Ithaca Reservoir, 1994 (Mapcase-folder 3)